hellyhansen.com 2016-06-23

# Privacy Policy - Helly Hansen.com

## Privacy Policy

This web site is the responsibility of Helly Hansen AS (hereinafter “Helly Hansen” or “we”). 

We take the privacy rights of our customers and users of our web site and our Helly Hansen applications (“APP”) very seriously. This Privacy Policy explains how information about you may be processed and for what purposes we may use identifiable and non-identifiable information. 

We collect and process personally identifiable information (“personal data”) in order to complete orders made by you, deal with enquiries made by you and to administer the Helly Hansen web site and APP. 

We do not sell, share, trade or rent any of your personal data, unless you have given your explicit consent hereto or unless otherwise as described in this Privacy Policy. 

We use advanced security measures to protect the security and confidentiality of personal data. 

**For EU/EEA Citizens:** Helly Hansen AS, is responsible for the handling of personal information gathered from and about you. Anders Olstad is the Controller in regard to processing of personal information gathered from and about you. Processing of your personal data is subject to Norwegian law which is based on the Directive 95/46/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council of 24 October 1995 on the protection of individuals with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data. If you have any questions related to our processing of personal data or this Privacy Policy, please contact (Finance/Legal department Helly Hansen by mail at Munkedamsveien 35, N-0250 Oslo, Norway or by e-mail at webmaster@hellyhansen.com. 

**For US Citizens:** Helly Hansen is responsible for the handling of personal information gathered from and about you. If you have any questions related to our processing of personal data or this Privacy Policy, please contact Helly Hansen by mail at 3703 I Street NW, Auburn, WA 98001 or by e-mail at webmaster@hellyhansen.com. 

**For Canadian Citizens:** Helly Hansen is responsible for the handling of personal information gathered from and about you. Our Marketing Manager may be contacted by mail at 8187 Swenson Way, Delta, BC V4G 1J5, attention, Marketing Manager; by or by phone 1-800-435 5901. 

### 1\. Collection of Personal data:

When you contact us, order from us, visit or use the Helly Hansen web site or download and use the APP we may ask you to give us certain personal data. It is voluntarily for you to provide us with your personal data and in certain cases is needed in order to provide a service to the customer. The processing of personal data is in order to fulfil an agreement with you, or is based on your consent, or is otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy. 

Depending on your reason for contacting us, Personal data may include your name, gender, size, country, billing address, e-mail address, Facebook ID, FB image, phone and mobile numbers, and shipping address if different from billing address. In addition, we may collect personal information from you in relation to payment; including credit card type, name of cardholder, card number, and expiration date and security code. 

We may also collect anonymous, non-personal data, such as your Internet Protocol (IP) address (first we collect your IP address and then we non-identify it by just using [the three first groups of numbers in the IP address]), browser type, and operating system through the use of “cookies.” We may use cookies to keep track of your visits to our website. A cookie is a small file that can be stored by your browser on your computer’s hard drive. Cookies may be used to compile anonymous statistics related to the use of our services or to your pattern of browsing on our website. When used in this manner you are not individually identified. Data collected in this manner is used only in aggregate form. The data is not combined with, or matched to, any of your personal data. You can usually change your browser's settings so that it will not accept cookies, although this may make it difficult for you to use some areas of the website. 

For statistical purposes we may also collect information to analyse traffic to our site. This information is not personally identifiable. 

When you download and use the APP, we need to store some personal data to make the activation run and remember who you are. This includes selected data that you have provided on your Facebook account such as your name, email address, Facebook ID, gender, country.  Other personal data uploaded depends on the APP you have installed and please check the respective game rules for specific data that will be processed in this case. (see specific game rules). 

### 2\. Use of your personal data 

We use your personal data for the following purposes: 

  * To process and fulfil your order. 
  * To bill you for our products and services and collect outstanding debts. 
  * To administer your account with Helly Hansen 
  * Your contact information may be used by us to communicate with you regarding your order status or to provide you with related customer service, to send you information about Helly Hansen relating to your order or inquiry. 
  * In our feedback form, order catalogue form and customer service sections, we may ask you to give us contact information, for example your name, phone number, e-mail address or postal address, in order for us to be able to respond to your inquiry. 
  * For product development or enhancement, for content improvement, and to customize content and layout of our site. 
  * When you sign up for online services like e-mail newsletters, we use your e-mail address to send the information you requested. 
  * Contact information may be used to send you information about Helly Hansen and to send you occasional promotional material via e-mail and/or mailings, such as information about special offers which we think you might find valuable or information about functionality changes to the website, or information about upcoming events or contests sponsored by Helly Hansen. 
  * To provide you with the APP's offered features at any point in time. 

**For EU/EEA Citizens:** Electronic marketing communications will only be sent to our existing customers. If you are not an existing customer with us, we will only contact you or send information if you have given your explicit consent hereto. You may opt out of receiving future e-mails and/or mailings; see the opt out section of this policy. 

**For Canadian Citizens:** If you have not opted out of receiving marketing materials, we may also use your contact information to send you occasional promotional material which we think you might find valuable, such as information about special offers, promotions and contests from us, and our affiliates. 

### 3\. Right to Access and Correct Personal Data

Upon request by e-mail or by mail to the addresses set out above, we will provide you with a summary of any personal data collected and retained by us regarding you. You may modify, correct, or update your personal information or request to have your personal information removed from our database. Helly Hansen will only send copies of personal information to the e-mail address on file for the visitor name associated with it. 

### 4\. Non-disclosure to third parties

Unless we have your express consent via e-mail or opt-in, we will not disclose your personal data to third parties. We may also disclose or transfer your data to data processors or to business partners who are acting on our behalf, subject to a Data Processor Agreement. These entities are prohibited from using your personal information for any purpose other than to provide services to you on our behalf and they are required to protect personal information collected by them on behalf of us or disclosed to them by us and to comply with the general privacy principles described in this Privacy Policy. None of these entities may process information about you provided by us on their own behalf and for their own purposes, without your express consent. 

Except as described in this Privacy Policy, we will not transfer, sell, rent or trade your personal data to others without your express consent. We may provide aggregate statistics about our customers, sales, traffic patterns and related site information to reputable third parties but these statistics will include no personally identifying information. 

Helly Hansen reserves the right to disclose your personal data to third parties to the extent that disclosure is required by law, to enforce our website policies, to protect yours or others’ rights, property or safety; such information may also be disclosed and/or transferred in the event that Helly Hansen merges or acquires (or is acquired) by another entity. 

### 5\. Transfer of data outside your jurisdiction

**For EU/EEA Citizens:** For any of the above purposes we may send your information internationally, including countries outside the EU/EEA. Some of these countries outside the EU/EEA may offer a lower level of protection of personal information than in your home country. If you do not consent to the transfer of your personal information to such countries where appropriate, please see the opt out section of this policy. 

**For Canadian Citizens:** For any of the purposes set out in this privacy policy, we, or one of our affiliates or an unaffiliated service provider, may process and store your personal information outside of the province in which you reside and/or outside of Canada, and under the laws of those other jurisdictions, in certain circumstances courts, law enforcement agencies, regulatory agencies or security authorities in those other provinces or foreign jurisdictions may be entitled to access your personal information. 

### 6\. Retention and Security of your information

We retain your personal information for no longer than as necessary to fulfil the purpose(s) for which it was collected and to comply with applicable laws, and your consent to such purposes(s) remains valid after termination of our relationship with you. If the personal data shall not thereafter be stored in pursuance of the Archives Act or other legislation, they shall be erased. 

We endeavour to take all reasonable steps to protect your privacy. We follow generally accepted security procedures and use reasonable efforts to prevent loss, theft and unauthorized access to information which you have given us, such as firewalls, access control procedures and cryptography. This is to prevent loss, theft, unauthorized access or unlawful processing of your personal information. We also limit access to your personal information to selected employees or representatives. 

### 7\. Links to Third Party Sites

This website may offer links to other third party websites. You should be aware that operators of linked websites may also collect your personal information (including information generated through the use of cookies) when you visit their websites. We are not responsible for how such third parties collect, use or disclose your personal information, so it is important to familiarize yourself with their privacy policies before providing them with your personal information. 

### 8\. Children's personal data

Helly Hansen’s family of websites may be used by children under the age of 18, and therefore there may be some personal data of children under the age of 18 used and processed by us in relation to their visiting the Helly Hansen website and or buying product off the web shop. We will require the parental consent of any child who is under the age of 15 and who visits our website and or web shop. Promotional rules for all APPS require a minimum age of 18 to participate. 

### 9\. Your consent

We will not, as a condition of the supply of a product or service, require you to consent to the collection, use or disclosure of information beyond that required to fulfil the explicitly specified and legitimate purposes for which the information is being provided. By purchasing our products or accessing or using our website you consent to the collection, storage, use and disclosure of your personal information by us in the manner set out in this privacy policy. Should we change our privacy policy, we will post the changes on this website so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use and under what circumstances we disclose it. The policy posted at any time or from time to time via this website shall be deemed to be the policy then in effect. 

### 10\. Opt out

We provide you with the opportunity to opt out of receiving promotional and marketing information from us at the time that we collect your personal information and each time we send you such information. If you have previously given us consent to disclose your personal data to any third parties, you may withdraw your consent to the collection, use or disclosure of your personal information by us (subject to legal or contractual restrictions and excluding any mandatory disclosure to government agencies or third parties if a law, regulation, search warrant, subpoena or court order legally requires or authorizes us to do so). You can do this by sending an e-mail to webmaster@hellyhansen.com. 

**EU/EEA Citizens:** Helly Hansen AS, Munkedamsveien 35, N-0250 Oslo, Norway, +47 69249000 

**US Citizens:** Helly Hansen (U.S.) Inc., 3703 I Street NW, Auburn, WA 98001, 1-800-435-5901 

**Canadian Citizens:** Helly Hansen Leisure Canada, 8187 Swenson Way, Delta, BC V4G 1J5, 1-800-4355901
